Guide to the Clarence Beverly Davison Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Clarence Beverly Davison Family papers
1856-1978
MS 1438
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
The papers primarily consist of scrapbooks that document the student lives of Clarence Beverly Davison, Sr. (Class of 1890) and Clarence Beverly Davison, Jr.(Class of 1918) in Sheffield Scientific School at Yale University and the military career of Clarence Beverly Davison, Jr. The scrapbooks contain clippings, correspondence, memorabilia, objects, and ephemera. The collection also includes the unpublished "Beverly: A Narrative Biography" by Peter G. Knox, Jr. and a small amount of family correspondence.
Davison, Clarence Beverly, 1869-1938
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Peter G. Knox and Peter G. Knox, Jr., 1986.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers primarily consist of scrapbooks that document the student lives of Clarence Beverly Davison Sr. and Clarence Beverly Davison, Jr. in Sheffield Scientific School at Yale University and the military career of Clarence Beverly Davison Jr. The scrapbooks contain clippings, correspondence, memorabilia, objects, and ephemera. The collection also includes the unpublished "Beverly: A Narrative Biography" by Peter G. Knox, Jr. and a small amount of family correspondence.
Biographical / Historical
Clarence Beverly Davison (1869-1938) graduated from Sheffield Scientific School in 1890 and lived the greater part of his life in New York City as a partner in the firm of Davison and Murphy, coffee importers. Clarence Beverly Davison (1896-1974) graduated from Sheffield Scientific School with the class of 1918. He trained with the Yale Batteries (Connecticut National Guard, 10th Field Artillery) in Tobyhanna, Pennsylvania and fought in World War I with Battery C, 301st Field Artillery, American Expeditionary Forces.
Arrangement
Arranged by record type.
Scrapbooks; Davison, Clarence Beverly, 1869-1938; Davison, Clarence Beverly, 1896-1974; Knox, Peter G.; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Family correspondence, 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Beverly: A Narrative Biography [unpublished manuscript by Peter G. Knox, Jr.], 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Davison, Clarence Beverly, Jr.
      - Yale Batteries [10th Field Artillery, Connecticut National Guard], 1916 (Box 2)
      - Family and childhood [includes Hotchkiss School materials, Yale memorabilia, and family papers], 1856-1918 (Box 3)
      - World War I [Battery C, 301st Field Artillery, American Expeditionary Forces], 1918 (Box 4)
    - Davidson, Clarence Beverly, Sr. [includes Yale memorabilia, clothing, clippings, and ephemera], 1887-1890 (Box 5)
  - Photograph of Connecticut National Guard, 1916 August 16 (Box 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Panoramic view of Connecticut National Guard training in Pennsylvania.